Partha Protim Paul

Associate Software Engineer

I am passionate about competitive programming and solving programming problems with logical and analytical capabilities that make use of data structure and algorithm expertise. I've engaged in several onsite programming competitions and solved over 1500 problems in front of different online judges.

ppartha101@gmail.com

(+880) 1701001168

Bonosree, Dhaka, Bangladesh Q

linkedin.com/in/partha-protim-paul-6039a4148 in

github.com/partha-sust16 (7)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer Orbitax Bangladesh Ltd.

07/2020 - Present.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Tasks

- Working at a Tax Solution Platform with microservices.
- Working as both frontend and backend with Angular and

Intern Software Engineer Orbitax Bangladesh Ltd.

01/2020 - 06/2020.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Tasks

- Worked in a cross platform mobile app with react native.
- This app contains messaging, push notifications and basic feature of a product called DAC6

EDUCATION

BSc in Software Engineering Shahjalal University of Science and Technology

01/2017 - 02/2021, CGPA: 3.89 out of 4.00

Thesis and Problem Solving Activities

- Thesis Topic: Event Driven Proactive Auto-Scaling in Cloud Application.
- Codeforces: Max Rating 1810 https://codeforces.com/profile/PPnT
- UVA: Problem Solved 330+ https://uhunt.onlinejudge.org/id/891541
- VJudge: Problem Solved 750+ https://vjudge.net/user/PP Paul
- CodeChef: Max Rating 1608 https://www.codechef.com/users/pp_paul
- Solved Around 1500 Problems in different Online Judge
- Participated in more than 100 online contests and around 15 Onsite Contests.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2nd Runner up in App Development Contest IUT (2019)
- Participate in ACM ICPC Dhaka Regional (2019)
- 19th Place in SUB ICPC (2018)
- 10th Place in NEUB Junior Programming Contest (2017)

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

COVID-19 Sahajjo (01/2020 - 05/2020)

- This application to provide some emergency contacts and information to help people in Bangladesh in the situation of COVID- 19.
- GitHub: https://github.com/swesust/covid-19-help-supportbd/releases/tag/1.0

Health Care (06/2019 - 12/2019)

- The application aims to deliver necessary health guide posts to it's user during pregnancy with scheduled mail
- The user can also post about their problems and other's can comment in it.
- The user can store images and create a timeline from it.
- This application was developed with Spring boot and ReactJs and mySQL.

Health Kit (01/2019 - 08/2019)

- This project was developed to maintain one's medical history via online.
- Can make reservation with the doctor without calling phone and the doctor can prescribe the patient via this.
- Emergency support to nearest medical with Push
- notification. This project was developed with Java for android
- GitHub: https://github.com/Partha-SUST16/Health_KIT

Book Shop Management (01/2019 - 06/2019)

- This project is to help the book shop owner to manage their sells, revenue and other functionalities to sell to online customer.
- A bookshop management project with PHP and PostgreSQL database.
- GitHub: https://github.com/Partha-SUST16/Book-Shop-Management

Easy Rent (07/2019 - 12/2019)

- This application was basically develop to solve house renting hassle for bachelors in a new area.
- This application contains all the house available for renting along with map location and description.
- The house owner can post about his house available for renting with images and description.
- Developed with Java for android.
- Github: https://github.com/Partha-SUST16/Easy-Rent